GREG MROWCZYNSKI

Nuneaton | 07492 204 194 | greg19850@gmail.com

Web: www.gregmdev.co.uk | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/greg-mrowczynski | Github: www.github.com/greg19850

Profile

Creative, detail-oriented Software Developer, with proven team work and problem solving experience, gained in various roles and environments, during years of professional career. In 2022 I began career switch into tech industry by learning coding, practising and working as freelance Web Developer. In January 2023 I joined Northcoders Software Development Bootcamp to support this change. Thanks to soft skills developed during my education and professional career, I can easily adapt to new environments and different programming languages. I enjoy picking up new skills in the pursuit of self-improvement.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript | Python (currently learning) | PHP (currently learning)

Front-end: JavaScript | React.js | Vue.js | HTML5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap 4 & 5 | SASS/SCSS | TypeScript

Back-end: Node.is | Express.is | PostgreSQL | Postman | Insomnia | Deployment

Testing: Jest | Supertest

Other skills: Object Orientated Programming | Problem Solver | Agile practices | Collaborative Team

Player | Pair Programming | Version Control

Work history

Software Developer

01/2023 - 04/2023

Northcoders – Birmingham

Intensive industry focused bootcamp, which gave me opportunity to learn best practices in full-stack software development, in agile / pair programming environment. Course improved my problem solving skills, and ability to effectively work in a fast-paced high performance tech team.

- Front-end projects, built with use of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JavaScript frameworks, like React, with use of both functional and object-orientated programming.
- Back-end projects using Node, Express.
- Creating and using databases with use of PostgreSQL.
- All projects created in Test Driven Development environment.
- Improved code quality through automated testing, reviewing and validation.
- Wrote clean, clear and well-tested code for various projects.

Main Tech Projects:

Skin Cancer Awareness app – Full Stack aplication, comparing user skin photo, with database photos, and assessing probability of skin cancer.

- Front-end: Single Page Application made in JavaScript / Vue.js
- Backend: Express.js, Deep Learning App, made with Pyhon/PyTorch/Flask for results analysis, MySQL database, hosted on AWS cloud server.

NC Articles Back-end - Back-end Project with use of Express/PSQL project including:

• RESTful API backend that connects to sever and database through various endpoints. Hosting tables like: articles, users, categories, comments. Build with Model-View-Controller pattern.

NC Articles Front-end - Front-end Project, with use of React.js.

• UI/front-end interface that connects with sever. Build with React, styled with CSS.

Front-End Web Developer

02/2022 - 01/2023

Freelance – Nuneaton

Freelance front-end web development. I have worked on web projects for clients, with use of front-end technologies: JavaScript, React, CSS.

- Created websites by harnessing HTML, CSS and JavaScript skills.
- Communicated with clients in development process, to confirm creative proposals, and best design ideas.
- Built front-end for catalogue of articles and services of Sporivia company offering sport surfaces.
- Rebuilt medical online brochure with use of React, initially written in HTML/CSS.
- Image optimisation and clean coding practices.
- Created multiple sample projects for portfolio website.

Sample of my projects (all projects available on my personal website, and my GitHub page):

- Movie tickets booking page (with use of local storage).
- Exchange Rate Calculator (Rest API).
- Slot machine (Object Oriented Programming).

Quality Engineer

LEVC – Coventry

- Participated in multi-disciplinary defect reviews to discern and address root causes.
- Supported quality team members during corrective action updates.
- Facilitated process improvements to successfully decrease errors.
- Suppliers PPAP weekly approval rate increased by 200% (from 2 to 6).

Quality Engineer

09/2018 - 04/2022

04/2022 - 12/2022

IMK Automotive - Coventry

- Led problem-solving activities to quickly identify and permanently resolve quality and productivity issues. Reduced customer issues amount by 20% in 2 years.
- Cost of quality reduced by 30 % in first year, and another 20% in year 2.
- 100% of PPAP's for new projects sent in time to customers.
- Completing 8D's average time reduced from 28 to 14 days.
- Developed traceability documentation to aid in investigating faults and defects.
- Supported quality team members during corrective action updates.
- Built strong rapport with team members, management and clients to facilitate efficiency and productivity.

Education

Master of Business Administration: Applied Mathematics
Warsaw School of Business And Int. Finances - Warsaw, Poland